Muhammad Shazrin Bin Shoffie

Mobile: +65 9010 5250 Email: mshazrinbs@gmail.com

Websites: linkedin.com/in/muhammad-shazrin, github.com/shazxrin, shazxrin.me

SUMMARY

Recent Computer Science graduate from National University of Singapore. Demonstrated expertise and proficiency in frontend and backend Web Development; with experience in React, in-depth background in Java and its Java Virtual Machine, and professional experience with the Spring ecosystem. Possess knowledge and exposure in DevOps with tools such as Linux, Docker and Kubernetes. Passionate in Al/Machine Learning specifically in Natural Language Processing.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Aug 2021 - May 2024

Bachelor of Computing in Computer Science (Distinction)

- Specializations: Multimedia Information Retrieval (NLP/AI)
- GPA: 4.15/5.0

Ngee Ann Polytechnic

May 2016 - May 2019

Diploma In Information Technology (Merit)

- Specializations: Solutions Architect
- GPA: 3.93/4.0

SKILLS

Frontend Development

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Remix, Node.js, Vite, Vitest, Jest, Playwright

Backend Development

Go, Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, JUnit, Hibernate, Gradle, Maven, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ActiveMQ

DevOps

Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Git, CI/CD

Machine Learning

• Python, Numpy, Pandas, SciKit, PyTorch, Hugging Face

WORK EXPERIENCE

Univers Pte. Ltd, Software Engineer Intern

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Maintained microservices with <u>Spring Boot</u>, <u>Hibernate</u> and <u>PostgreSQL</u> and deployed with <u>Docker</u> and <u>Kubernetes</u>.
- Facilitated development of a new Extract-Transform-Load (ETL) tool with ability to scale in cloud native environment.

CrimsonLogic Pte. Ltd, Software Engineer Intern

Mar 2018 - Sep 2018

- Maintained full-stack web applications with <u>Spring Framework</u>, <u>Hibernate</u>, <u>MySQL</u>, <u>HTML</u> and <u>JavaScript</u>.
- Ensured bug-free codebase with static analysis and test cases for code coverage, reducing reported bugs.
- Improved existing search feature by writing optimal SQL queries, improving search results speed.

PORTFOLIO

Personal Website, shazxrin.me

• Built a personal website portfolio using React and Remix, deployed on Vercel.

Home Lab Dec 2023 - Present

- Administrate a personal home lab for running personal applications with Linux, and Docker.
- Setup private networking with <u>Tailscale</u> and <u>NextDNS</u>, and reverse proxy for personal applications using <u>Caddy</u>.

Bloom, github.com/shazxrin/bloom

Aug 2023 - Present

Created a personal time and habit tracking web application with React, Spring Boot, Kotlin, PostgreSQL and Docker.

Cyberwarrior, github.com/shazxrin/cyberwarrior

April 2024 - Present

• Developed a web based card game to educate about cybersecurity with <u>React</u>, <u>Python</u> and <u>FastAPI</u> for the Total Defence module.

TrackTogether, github.com/very-indecisive-studios/tracktgt

April 2024 - Present

• Developed a multimedia (books, game and movies) manager web application with <u>React</u>, <u>C#</u>, <u>ASP.NET</u>, <u>MySQL</u> and <u>Docker</u> for the Independent Software Development module.